<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CIS 188: DevOps</title><link>https://cis188.org/</link><description>Recent content on CIS 188: DevOps</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cis188.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Final Project Presentations</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec14/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec14/</guid><description>Coming soon!</description></item><item><title>Special Topic: TBD</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec13/</guid><description>Coming soon!</description></item><item><title>No Class - Thanksgiving Break</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec12/</guid><description>Enjoy Thanksgiving break!</description></item><item><title>Special Topic: Zero Trust</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec11/</guid><description>No school!</description></item><item><title>Special Topic: CDKs</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec10/</guid><description>Coming soon!</description></item><item><title>Advanced Kubernetes</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec09/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec09/</guid><description>Coming soon!</description></item><item><title>Continuous Integration / Continuous Deployment</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec08/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec08/</guid><description>Lecture Eight: CI/CD Developer Experience Reproducibility through automation is one of the most important goals of DevOps we&amp;rsquo;ve discussed throughout the course. When it comes to deployment, though, there are quite a few steps that we need to keep in mind:
Make code change Test code Build Docker image Tag Docker image Push to Docker Hub Update Kubernetes manifests to new Docker image tag Apply updated manifests Importantly, steps 3-7 are the same every time we deploy our code.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring and Observability</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec07/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec07/</guid><description>Coming soon!</description></item><item><title>The Cloud</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec06/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec06/</guid><description>Lecture Six: Cloud Kubernetes Traditional Infrastructure Traditionally, from the beginning of the web in the 1990s up through 2009 or 2010, traditional server infrastructure was oriented around physical machines. There are three general steps in terms of complexity within this traditional structure: the &amp;ldquo;server under a desk&amp;rdquo;, colocation centers, and datacenters.
&amp;ldquo;Server under the desk&amp;rdquo; The &amp;ldquo;server under a desk&amp;rdquo; is exactly what it sounds like. Developers can (and did) set up static IP addresses through their internet service providers (ISPs) and simply plug in a server, expose its HTTP ports to the internet, and serve traffic.</description></item><item><title>Practical Kubernetes</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec05/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec05/</guid><description>Lecture Five: Practical Kubernetes We covered the conceptual foundation and some of the basic Kubernetes resources last week, and this week we&amp;rsquo;ll be diving into more concepts and resource types in Kubernetes that build on top of the foundation we built. Each resource we cover will have an associated example with requisite yaml. Please make sure to also check out the Kubernetes documentation as well! The important thing isn&amp;rsquo;t to memorize the yaml, but to understand the concepts so we can extend our understanding of what Kubernetes can do.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes fundamentals</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec04/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec04/</guid><description>Lecture Four: Kubernetes What is Kubernetes? At the most basic level, Kubernetes is a tool for orchestrating containers. In most scenarios these are Docker containers, but we can actually use Kubernetes to orchestrate any container that complies to the API specification (even VMs!). This tool will take us from running containers locally to running containers in production.
Pods A pod in Kubernetes is the most basic unit of work. They are tight couplings of containers: this means they are containers running on the same machine (node) sharing the same network (though they do not share the same filesystem).</description></item><item><title>Reproducibility: Docker Compose</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec03/</guid><description>Lecture Three: Docker Compose Limitations of Docker as a production run system We&amp;rsquo;ve seen how useful Docker is as a tool and the reasons that we&amp;rsquo;d want to use it in production. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t solve all of our problems. Take this docker run invocation, for example:
$ docker run -it \ --name=letsencrypt \ --cap-add=NET_ADMIN \ -e PUID=1000 \ -e PGID=1000 -e TZ=Europe/London \ -e URL=walthome.duckdns.org \ -e SUBDOMAINS=wildcard \ -e VALIDATION=duckdns \ -e DUCKDNSTOKEN=youwillnevergetthis \ -e EMAIL=pwpon500@gmail.</description></item><item><title>Docker Containers</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec02/</guid><description>Lecture Two: Docker Portability Recall all of the issues that we&amp;rsquo;ve run into trying transfer code that we developed on our local machine to a remote host in the cloud. We want to be able to take our application code and seamlessly run it on another machine. Along with Python dependencies, we needed to make sure that system resources, including Python and Poetry themselves, were also installed as expected. How can we avoid all of the dependency and versioning issues we ran into when we manually deployed to EC2?</description></item><item><title>HTTP</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec01/</guid><description>Lecture One: Networking 7 Layers of the OSI Model The internet is built in layers that allow us to abstract away a lot of the complexity that is inherent to networks. One common model for layers is the OSI Model (from top to bottom):
Application: End user later (HTTP, FTP, SSH, DNS) Presentation: Syntax layer (SSL, SSH, IMAP, FTP, JPEG) Session: Synch and send to port (APIs, sockets) Transport: End-to-end connections (TCP, UDP, QUIC) Network: Packets (IP, ICMP, IPSec, IGMP) Data Link: Frames (Ethernet, PPP, Switch, Bridge) Physical: Physical structure (Coax, Fiber, Wireless, Hubs, Repeaters) Internet Protocol (IP) IP is the lowest level of abstraction that we will uncover in this course.</description></item><item><title>Course Intro, Python Basics</title><link>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/lectures/lec00/</guid><description>Lecture Zero: Introduction Housekeeping Grade breakdown:
50% homework (5 assignments, 10% per homework released on GitHub and submitted on Gradescope) 40% final project 10% participation Class is curved.
Post questions on Piazza (but not for debugging, but for conceptual questions on the homeworks or lecture clarifications) or some to OH:
Peyton/Will: Sunday 2pm-4pm ET Armaan/Campbell: Thursday 6pm-8pm ET What is DevOps? Breaking down the wall between developers (people writing code) and operations (people releasing and deploying code into production and making sure it is reliable).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cis188.org/staff/armaan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/staff/armaan/</guid><description>Wrangling open source mantainers</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cis188.org/staff/campbell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/staff/campbell/</guid><description>Prefers alternating between tabs and spaces</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cis188.org/staff/goeller/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/staff/goeller/</guid><description>Cries in 1&amp;rsquo;s and 0&amp;rsquo;s</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cis188.org/staff/peyton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/staff/peyton/</guid><description>Lost in the zero trust sauce</description></item><item><title>Syllabus</title><link>https://cis188.org/syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cis188.org/syllabus/</guid><description>For a list of assignments and when they are due check the course schedule.
Meetings Course meetings will be every Wednesday from 5:15-6:45pm ET. Office hours will be held biweekly unless announced otherwise. Details can be found on our logistics Piazza post.
Topics Covered HTTP Containerization Docker Declarative Infrastructure Kubernetes Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment Cloud Fundamentals Infrastructure Monitoring Grading 50% Homework 40% Final Project 10% Participation Homework assignments will consist of medium-size projects that lead students through the implementation and application of concepts and tools discussed in lectures, and will be graded on correctness and completeness.</description></item></channel></rss>